A Guide to the Harry W. Frantz papers FA1168
Rockefeller Archive Center
Harry W. Frantz papers
1941-1964
Rockefeller Archive Center
Frantz, Harry W.
Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich) (1908-1979)
FA1168
3 Cubic Feet 2 standard record storage boxes, 1 letter document box.
Biographical / Historical
Harry W. Frantz was Director of the Press Division of the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA). Frantz also served as an associate of Nelson A. Rockefeller.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated to the Rockefeller family archives by Harry W. Frantz, May 12, 1969. Ingested by RAC in 1982 as Accession 1982:006, with an official instrument of donation dated March 9, 1983.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
The collection primarily documents Frantz work with the Press Division of the Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) and the State Department during World War II as well as the United Nations Conference in San Francisco in 1945.
The Frantz papers consist of printed material, newspaper articles and clippings, reports, memoranda, photographs, press releases, and scrapbooks assembled by Harry W. Frantz in 1946 and much of which was re-assembled by Frantz in the 1960s. The collection also contains summary stories of work at the CIAA and other personal items by Harry W. Frantz, as well as documentation of Nelson A. Rockefeller 1964 Presidential Campain and his activities in the early 1950s.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
- Conference of Leaders of Inter-American Activities in the United States - Department of the U.S. Activities and Special Services Office of the CIAA, 1944 November 13-15 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- WWII - CIAA - Press Division - Content and Directives; Special Assignments; Addresses and Expositions, 1941-1943 (Assembled 1946 and 1962 June) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- WWII - CIAA - Department of State - Miscellaneous Documents, 1941-1945 (Assembled 1962 May-June) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- WWII - CIAA - Letters and Sketches about Harry W. Frantz Trips, 1942-1944 (Assembled 1962) (Box 1, Folder 4)
- WWII - CIAA - Argentine Journalists Tour of U.S, and Canada, 1943 (Assembled 1962) (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
- WWII - CIAA - Press Division, 1941-1945 (Assembled 1962) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- CIAA - Outline Report - Work of the Press Division, 1941 December-1945 February (Box 1, Folder 9)
- OIAA - Press Highlights, 1944 March-1945 March (Box 1, Folder 10)
- WWII - CIAA - Publications, 1941-1945 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- United Nations Meeting, San Francisco, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 13-16)
- United Nations Meeting, San Francisco, 1945 (Assembled 1962) (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
- WWII - State Department - Warren Mission to Argentina, 1945 April (Assembled 1962) (Box 2, Folder 19)
- WWII - State Department - Inter-American Conference on Problems of Peace and War (Chapultepec Conference), 1945 February-March (Assembled 1962) (Box 2, Folder 20-21)
- WWII - CIAA - Publications, 1941-1945 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
- WWII - CIAA - Press Division - Personal File of Harry W. Frantz, 1941-1944 (Assembled 1946 and 1962) (Box 2, Folder 24)
  Scope and Contents
  Scrapbook of miscellaneous photos, stories, letters, and memorabilia.
- WWII - Miscellaneous Newspaper Articles (including End of War), 1945 (Box 3, Folder 25-26)
- Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1950-1955 (Assembled 1966 March) (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Nelson A. Rockefeller - Presidential Campaign 1964, 1962-1964 (Assembled 1966 March) (Box 3, Folder 28)
- United Nations Meeting, San Francisco - Photo-Facsimile Edition of New York Times, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 29)